Karen McClellan

PRODUCT STRATEGY & DESIGN

karenmcclellan.com

karenmmcc@gmail.com (325) 716-0380

ABOUT

I design products that support healthy behavior change and bring delight into everyday experiences.

I believe great design begins as curiosity about people and the everevolving technical and cultural landscapes they live in. My job is to stay curious, reframe challenges, and uncover solutions.

EDUCATION

CMCI STUDIO @ UNIVERSITY OF COLORADO BOULDER

Boulder, CO | 2018-2019*
M.A., UX Design (STCM) / 4.0
*Graduating Aug 2019

SOUTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

Georgetown, TX | 2004–2008 B.A., English Literature / 3.8

SKILLS & TOOLS

Sketch / Figma / Invision / HTML, css, Js / Adobe Illustrator, After Effects, Photoshop

WORK EXPERIENCE

CACTUS INC.

June 2019 + Denver, Colorado

UX Design Apprentice

Lead design process for digital projects in an agency setting with a focus on behavioral change design.

CMCI STUDIO

Aug 2018 + Boulder, Colorado

UX Designer

Apply human-centered design process to digital projects for clients incl. POWDR Corp., Denver Intl. Airport, and Hopelab.

MENTORING MINDS

Apr 2015-Aug 2018 Remote

Marketing Manager

Managed a team of 5, including design and copy resources, in an agile environment to create and execute an omnichannel marketing strategy. Reported to C-suite.

Content Marketing Strategist

Developed content strategy for conversion funnel. Led IA and content strategy for e-commerce website redesign.

Public Relations Specialist

Pitched stories, managed media relations, and wrote marketing copy.

FIRST PRESBYTERIAN

May 2013–Apr 2015 Tyler, Texas

Director of Communication

Led communication strategy. Designed digital and print collateral. Designed and executed a comprehensive website redesign.

KNITTA

Apr 2009–Nov 2012 Austin, Texas

Technical Designer

Designed project specifications for custom textile art installations. Managed production and installation for art exhibitions.